<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Test Blog</title>
 <link href="http://joist.github.io//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://joist.github.io//"/>
 <updated>2014-03-08T02:41:30+11:00</updated>
 <id>http://joist.github.io/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Joist</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Dat Map</title>
   <link href="http://joist.github.io//dat-map"/>
   <updated>2014-03-08T02:00:01Z</updated>
   <id>http://joist.github.io//dat-map</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t want to spend weeks trying to implement a map again. With that in mind I&amp;#39;m just going to cobble something together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-cs-students.stanford.edu/%7Eamitp/game-programming/polygon-map-generation/demo.html&quot;&gt;amitp has a glorious map generator up on his site&lt;/a&gt; which I&amp;#39;ll just import from for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voronoi would take too long to implement and square is too blocky, but hex looks nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Such map, very biomes&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hex can easily, but kludgily, be crammed into a square hole by doubling and offsetting the cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Squared version of map&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works surprisingly well and is extremely effective. Here&amp;#39;s how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zoomed in to square cells&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each hex cell is sized up to 4 square cells (2x2) which can be considered a single super-cell. Then each other column is shifted by a single cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effect is that each super-cell touches 6 other super-cells by edge instead of 4, and 0 super-cells by corner, also instead of 4. The variance of the distances between cell centres reduces too, from ~40% to ~10%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll probably ignore the super-cells for now and just treat them as regular cells, but it makes biome transitions look much smoother than what going square from the beginning gets you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Square from beginning&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World</title>
   <link href="http://joist.github.io//hello-world+copy"/>
   <updated>2014-03-07T04:00:01Z</updated>
   <id>http://joist.github.io//hello-world copy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;#39;s that time of year again when I start a game project destined to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect to be sidetracked by real life within a month but I&amp;#39;ll be documenting my progress and most of everything will be thrown up on github to be perused at your leisure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
